这儿是什么地方？
What is this place?
(旧金山)
我生活中有不少荒唐事
My life doesn't really make sense.
嘿
Hey.
有段时间我常常问自己
I used to ask myself a lot of questions about that.
"斯科特 你离过婚又坐过牢 怎么就成复仇者了？"
"Scott, you're a divorced ex-con. How are you an Avenger?
"怎么就跟美国队长去穿越时空了？"
"Why are you time traveling with Captain America?
"这太荒唐了"
"That doesn't make sense."
我的生活发生了许多变化
A lot has changed about my life.
但不管走到哪儿 大家都会问我一件事
But everywhere I go, people ask me the same thing.
你能跟我的狗合影吗？
Can you take a picture with my dog?
"斯科特 你有什么打算？"
"Scott, what about now?
"以后干嘛？"
"What's next?
"接下来的路往哪儿走？"
"Where does the ride take you?"
我要是知道 那还有什么意思
If I knew that, it wouldn't be a ride.
加油
All right.
-这几年过得魔幻 人人都是 -嘿 你好 最近好吗？
-It's been a crazy few years. For everyone. -Hey, hi. How are you?
东西都帮你准备好了
Everything is ready for you.
你太贴心了
You're too much.
不用 不用
No, no, no.
我们不收你的钱
Your money's no good here.
-你还要跟我搞这套？ -当然要
-Are we still talking about that? -Yes, of course.
鲁宾 你最棒了
Rubin, you are the best.
谢谢你 蜘蛛侠
Thank you, Spider-Man.
现在让我们把时间花在重要的事上
So, let's make time for the stuff that really matters.
见见老朋友
Like friends.
发现一些新朋友
Friends you didn't even know you had.
(本世纪最佳员工 斯科特·朗 "蚁人")
记住在你背后推过你一把的人
Remember the people who got you here.
没有他们就没有今天的你
You couldn't have done it without them.
嘿 我就是个被芭斯罗缤炒了的家伙
Hey, I'm just a guy who got fired from Baskin-Robbins.
有时你就是会走运
Sometimes you just get lucky.
我就走运 遇见了霍普·凡·戴恩
I'm lucky I met Hope Van Dyne.
你们都认识她吧
I think you know who she is.
(皮姆凡戴恩基金会)
她拿回了她爸爸的公司
She's taken back her dad's company.
致力于用皮姆粒子改变世界
Now she's using the Pym Particle for global change.
很多人都说想拯救世界
A lot of people say they want to save the world...
而霍普每天都在这么做
but Hope, she saves it every day.
谢谢
Thank you.
(国际人道主义服务奖)
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
植树造林 平价住房 粮食生产
Reforestation. Affordable housing. Food production.
她不浪费一分一秒
She's not wasting a second.
我至今不敢相信
I still can't believe it.
这一切本来不可能发生
None of this should have happened.
可就是发生了
But it did.
这个世界还挺美好
It's a pretty good world.
还好我们救了它
I'm glad we saved it.
(城市之光书店)
我会怀念那些行动吗？
"Do I miss the action?
(斯科特·朗：不可忽视小人物)
有时会
"Sometimes.
复仇者联盟需要我时 我会去吗？
"Will I be there when the Avengers need me?
当然会
"Absolutely.
我永远不会背弃他们
"I'd never turn my back on them.
但现在 我只想当一个好爸爸
"But right now, the only job I want is being a dad.
我爱你 凯茜
"I love you, Cassie.
谢谢你成为我的英雄
"Thanks for being my hero.
对不起 我错过了你几年的生日
"And I'm sorry I missed some birthdays.
对天底下所有孩子们
"And for the rest of you kids out there...
给你们点小建议
"word of advice.
不要忽视小人物
"Look out for the little guy.
敢于犯错
"Make mistakes.
勇于冒险
"Take chances.
生活教会了我一件事
"Because if there's one thing life's taught me...
成长的空间 永远都有
"there's always room to grow."
抱歉 是我
Sorry, that's me.
(旧金山监狱)
监狱找我干嘛？
Why is jail calling?
朗！
Lang!
-朗！ -我在这儿
-Lang! -I'm here.
出来 跟我走
All right, come on. Let's go.
快点
Come on.
嘿 她没事吧？有什么消息？
Hey. Is she okay? Have you heard anything?
还没有
Not yet. No.
嗨 霍普 嘿 爸爸
Hi, Hope. Hey, Dad.
凯茜 怎么回事？
Cassie. What happened?
在这儿签字
Sign here.
就是进监狱那档子事
You know, just jail stuff.
还给我
Give it back.
我知道是你干的
I know it was you.
你确定？
Are you sure?
当时可不容易看清
I mean, it was kind of hard to see...
毕竟你们朝公园里的和平示威者扔了那么多催泪弹
through all that tear gas you fired into the park full of peaceful protestors.
它在哪儿？
Where is it?
真可怜 你肯定觉得很丢脸
I'm sorry. This must be really embarrassing for you.
不过我捡到了这个
I did find this though.
你把警车缩小了？
You shrank a cop car?
你怎么想的？
What were you thinking?
不然我该怎么办？袖手旁观？
What was I supposed to do? Look the other way?
他们半夜里驱赶无家可归露营的人
They were clearing out a homeless camp in the middle of the night.
-我不是说… -警察想把那些人赶去哪儿？
-No, I'm not saying that... -And where do they expect them to go?
他们在烁灭时没了家又不能怪他们
It's not their fault that they lost their homes in the Blip.
我知道
I know that.
现在没人租得起房 除了家财万贯的富二代
No one can even afford rent right now, unless you're some trust-fund asshole.
我不是要教你做事
I'm not telling you what to do.
-我只是想… -教她做事
-I'm just saying... -Telling her what to do.
教我做每一件事
Telling me exactly what to do.
不 你做你想做的
No, you do what you want.
我只是建议你换种方式
I'm suggesting another way to do it.
好吧
Okay.
我跟你妈妈保证过
You know, I promised your mom...
你只能在我们眼皮底下使用这些东西
that you would only use this stuff when one of us was around.
这种科技很危险
It's really dangerous tech.
我知道它很危险
I know it's dangerous.
万一被警察没收了呢？万一被你弄丢了呢？
What if the cops took it from you? What if you lost it?
我可没弄丢战衣
I didn't lose the suit.
你有战衣？
You have a suit?
等等 你还有战衣？
Wait, you have a suit?
我能照顾好自己 好吗？
I know how to take care of myself, okay?
相信我 我现在已经很熟练了
Trust me. I'm pretty good at it by now.
好痛
Ouch.
-我不是那个意思 对不起 -我知道
-I didn't mean it like that. I'm sorry. -I know.
没事 没关系
That's okay. It's all right.
我明白
I get it.
我只想让你过普通的生活
I just think you should get to have a normal life.
爸爸 我六岁时就有一个
Dad, a guy dressed like a bee...
穿得像蜜蜂的人跑到家里来杀我
tried to kill me in my room when I was six.
我的生活从没普通过
I've never had a normal life.
听点音乐吧？
How about some music?
那一刻 我只想着
"And in that moment, all I could think was...
浩克是怎么把我变成小宝宝的？
"'How did the Hulk turn me into a baby?
我会永远都是小宝宝吗？
"'Will I be a baby forever?
我是浩克的宝宝吗？
"Am I the Hulk's baby?"
爸爸 你在听你自己的书吗？
Dad, are you listening to your own book?
-但我早已做好准备 -嗯？不 这是…
-"But I was ready for anything. -Hmm? No, that's...
-这是电台节目 -史蒂夫和我关系变好了
-It's just the radio. -"Steve and I grew close over that."
-爸爸 快关掉 -奇怪
-Dad, turn it off. -It's so weird.
这个开关出问题了 关不掉
Something's wrong with this switch. It won't turn off.
叫你快关掉
I said turn it off.
你说什么？开响点？好吧
What's that? Turn it up? All right.
没过多久 来了一只太空浣熊
"A little after that, a raccoon from space showed up.
他大概不知道我叫什么
"I don't think he knew my name.
见到一只会说话的浣熊 我很开心
"I was just happy to meet a raccoon who could talk."
借过一下
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧
All right.
你的诺贝尔奖在路上
Your Nobel Prize is in the mail.
它最好是 我这招省了八块钱呢
It better be. I just saved eight bucks.
天啊 我真崇拜你
God, I admire you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我一直很怀念这些
I missed this.
量子领域没有比萨吗？
No pizza in the Quantum Realm?
没有 什么都没有
No. No anything.
妈妈 你可以跟我们说说
You know, Mom, you can talk about it.
如果你想的话
If you want.
亲爱的 我在那儿被困了三十年
Sweetheart, I spent 30 years down there.
现在我只想活好当下
I wanna live right now.
凯茜 你这次进监狱交新朋友了吗？
So, Cassie, did you make any new friends in the slammer this time?
外公
Grandpa.
这次？
"This time"?
难道还有上次？
Was there a last time?
上次其实不能算
I mean, last time barely counts.
我都不知道
I didn't know that.
你怎么没跟我说？
Why didn't you call me?
因为我料到你会这样
'Cause I knew you'd be like this.
其实我可以派蚂蚁去救你
I would've just broken you out with ants.
够了 开家庭会议
All right, you know what? Family meeting.
能开会谈谈吗？
Can we have a family meeting?
现在不就在谈吗？
Isn't that what we're doing?
但我想谈的是
Yeah, I mean about this.
大家放任她胡来的这种态度
About everybody being so fine with this.
听着 你想帮助别人 我明白
Look, you wanna help. I get it.
我懂 凯茜 我很理解
I do, Cassie. I really do.
我是怕你浪费人生
But I don't want you wasting your life.
我的人生至少还干了些事
At least I'm still trying to do something with mine.
我可是拯救过世界的
I literally saved the world.
真的吗？
Oh, did you?
从没听你提起过
Well, yeah, you never mentioned that before.
大家注意 斯科特拯救过世界
Hey, everybody, Scott saved the world.
感觉怎么样 斯科特？
How was that for you, Scott?
你应该出本书讲讲
You should write a book about it.
哈哈 真幽默
Ha ha. Hilarious.
你们没变成灰多亏了我 不用谢
Yeah, you're welcome for all not being dust.
那你现在在干嘛？
And what do you do now?
签名售书？
Sign books?
你还是当年那个勇闯维斯塔公司
Aren't you the guy who broke into VistaCorp?
大老远飞去德国
Aren't you the guy who flew all the way to Germany...
跟美国队长在机场打架的人吗？
just to fight Captain America at the airport?
是和美国队长並肩作战
Fight with Captain America at the airport.
我才不会跟美国队长打
Wouldn't fight Captain America.
我又没疯
Not insane.
还有很多人需要帮助 爸爸
People still need help, Dad.
至少我们还在努力做点有用的事
At least we're trying to do something that matters.
"我们"是谁？
Who's "we"?
你们三个在搞什么？
What are you three up to?
搞科学
Science.
用蚂蚁
With ants.
蚂蚁科学
Ant science.
我才不信呢
I don't believe you.
让他瞧瞧
Let's just show him.
它们在造什么？
What are they building?
是你在控制吗？
Are you doing this?
不是 都是它们自己搞的
Actually, no, they built their own tech.
蚂蚁很聪明
Pretty smart ants.
好了 在你们都…
Okay, so when you were all...
消失的那五年里 我闲着没事干
like, gone those five years, I had a lot of time.
就开始翻汉克外公以前写的日志
And I started reading Grandpa Hank's old journals...
彻底迷上了量子领域 然后…
and I got really into the Quantum Realm and...
量子领域？
The Quantum Realm?
我知道大家对那儿没好印象 怕你们着急我就没说
I know we all have a history there, and I didn't want to freak anyone out...
其实我们一直在研究
but we've been talking about it.
她爱提问题 好吗？
She had some questions, okay?
别人受我启发 我拦不住啊
I can't help if people are inspired by me.
你一直在研究量子领域？
So, you've been studying the Quantum Realm?
怎么不来问我？
Why didn't you ask me about it?
我问过你 妈妈
I tried, Mom.
很多次
A lot.
每次你都不愿意说
You never wanted to talk about it.
凯茜很有求知欲
Cassie's just been curious...
我们就给了她一些指点
and we gave her some pointers.
这不是单纯的蚂蚁科学 对吗 亨利？
This isn't exactly ant science, is it, Henry?
你知道量子领域有多危险
You know how dangerous the Quantum Realm is.
我们都知道 妈妈
Yeah, we all do, Mom.
谁也没说要去量子领域
Nobody's going to the Quantum Realm.
所以我们造了这个
That's why we made this.
类似探索深空或深海的探测器
It's like a satellite for deep space or the ocean.
但它探索量子领域
But Quantum.
只要有张地图
We just need a map.
我们就能探索研究整个量子领域
And then we can study and explore the entire Quantum Realm.
再也不用亲自去了
Never even have to go.
你女儿在地下室里造了个亚原子哈勃望远镜
Your daughter built a subatomic Hubble Telescope in a basement.
要是你们消失时我有这种工具
You know, if I had something like this when you were gone...
我就能找到你了
then I could have found you.
太了不起了
It's amazing.
我做梦都想不到
I'm blown away.
这要怎么用？
How does it work?
有点像以前家里那台双向无线电
It's kinda like that two-way radio we used to have.
从这儿发个信号过去
You send a signal down from here...
收集到数据后再发送回来
and then it collects the data, and it sends it back.
等一下
Wait. Wait a minute.
你在向量子领域发送信号？
You're sending a signal down to the Quantum Realm?
对
Yeah.
-马上关掉 -珍妮…
-Shut it down now. -Janet...
-为什么要关掉… -怎么了？
-Why would we shut it... -What's wrong?
赶紧关掉！
You have to turn it off!
别激动 告诉我们怎么了！
Stop and tell us what's wrong!
珍妮？
Janet?
有些事我早该告诉…
There's something I should have told...
爸爸？
Dad?
不！
No!
-不！ -妈妈！
-No! -Mom!
不！
No!
见鬼！
Damn it!
爸爸？
Dad?
爸爸！
Dad!
凯茜
Cassie.
爸爸！
Dad!
爸爸 起来
Oh, Dad. Come on.
好了
Okay.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah. I'm okay.
这儿是什么地方？
Where are we?
妈妈！
Mom!
爸爸！
Dad!
霍普 我在这儿
Hope. Over here.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我们应该死了才对
We should be dead.
为什么还没死？
Why aren't we?
不知道
I don't know.
这儿是我想的那地方吗？
Are we where I think we are?
应该说是的 但…
I would say yes...
上次来时不是这样
but it wasn't like this.
珍妮！
Janet!
妈妈！
Mom!
珍妮！
Janet!
妈妈！
Mom!
待在这儿别动
Do not move.
得找到斯科特和凯茜
We need to find Scott and Cassie.
马上
Right now.
霍普？
Hope? Hope?
汉克？能听见吗？
Hank? Can you hear me?
-有人能听见吗？ -天啊
-Can anyone hear me? -Oh, my God.
-没事 -现在怎么办？
-It's okay. -What are we gonna do?
没事 我们没事的
It's okay. It's okay. We're okay.
我们没事 会没事的
We're okay. It's gonna be okay.
你说太多遍"没事"了
You're saying "okay" too much.
好吧 没事 我就是陈述事实
Okay. All right. Okay. Well, it's 'cause we are.
我们没事
We're okay.
我们很好
We are fine.
我们会找到他们 然后回家
Hey, we're gonna find them, and we're gonna go home.
趁现在看看风景
In the meantime, look around.
这儿多美
It's beautiful.
这儿就像野外
All right? We're outside.
就当是露营 我们喜欢露营
It's like we're camping. We love camping.
我们从来没露营过
We've never been camping.
但我们一直都说要去
But we've always talked about it.
那个太阳是在动吗？
Is that sun moving?
退后！
Get back!
老天！
Oh, my God.
这好像不是太阳！
I don't think this is a sun!
没事
It's fine.
-爸爸！ -没问题
-Dad! -Honey, it's okay.
问题不大
Still okay.
爸爸 天啊
Dad. Oh, my God.
真诡异
That was weird.
快跑
Run.
量子领域里还有量子住民？
There's Quantum people in the Quantum Realm?
是啊
Yeah.
我也是第一次知道
I didn't know that either.
刚才那是什么 妈妈？
What was that back there, Mom?
那艘飞船在找什么？
What was that ship looking for?
小点声
Keep your voice down.
你还说这儿什么都没有
You said there was nothing down here.
你为什么不告诉我们这里的事？
Why didn't you tell us about all of this?
霍普 我以后会解释的 但现在
Hope, I will explain everything, but right now...
-拜托你相信我就好 -你要我怎么相信你！
-I just need you to trust me. -Then make me trust you!
大家都冷静点 有话好好说
Let's just calm down, all right? We can talk about this...
现在没时间说话了 亨利
We don't have time to talk, Henry.
你必须告诉我们到底…
No, you need to tell us what's...
你为什么不听话？我叫你别靠近这儿
Why didn't you listen? I told you to stay away from here.
珍妮 都是我的错
Janet, I'm so sorry.
我应该告诉你我们的研究 我没想到…
I should have told you what we were doing. I had no idea...
我知道 这事…
I know. It's...
回头再谈
We'll talk later.
现在我们要一起行动
Right now, we stick together...
找到斯科特和凯茜
we find Scott and Cassie...
然后回家 好吗？
and we go home. Okay?
-好吗？ -好吗？
-Okay? -Okay?
-好的 -很好
-Okay. -Okay.
跟紧了
Stay close.
太不可思议了
This is incredible.
我研究量子领域这么多年
I've studied the Quantum Realm for years.
怎么从没看到过这些？
Why didn't I see any of this?
你能看到的地方还不够深
You weren't able to look deep enough.
还没穿过虚空和亚原子系统
Not through the Void and Subatomica.
这儿有许多个世界
There are worlds here...
世界之中还有世界
worlds within worlds.
这里超脱于时间与空间之外
It's a place outside time and space.
是一个不为人知的神秘宇宙
It's a secret universe...
隐藏在我们的世界下
beneath ours.
放开我！
Hey, get your hands off me!
凯茜？
Cassie?
我女儿呢？
Where's my daughter?
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
凯茜？
Cassie?
我女儿在哪儿？
Where's my daughter?
凯茜！
Cassie!
爸爸！
Dad!
凯茜！
Cassie!
把悟汁喝了
Drink the ooze.
什么？
What?
交给我就行
I'll handle this.
妈妈
Mom.
感情好就捅一刀吗？
Was that a good stab?
我搞到车了
I got us a ride.
他很亲人
He's friendly.
这车够别致的
Quite a ride.
你可是第一个骑着蚂蚁到处飞的人
Says the man who invented flying on the back of an ant.
我喜欢蚂蚁
I like ants.
我也喜欢你这一点 穿上
And I love that you love them. Here.
方便混进当地人里
These will help us blend in.
我们要坐这东西去哪儿？
Where exactly are we going on this?
我有个老朋友住得离这儿不远
We're not too far from an old friend of mine.
想知道斯科特和凯茜的下落
If anyone's heard where Scott and Cassie are...
就得找他
it'll be him.
您先请
After you.
上车吧 蚁人
Saddle up, Ant-Man.
放开我！
Let me go! Let me go!
我听不懂你在说什么！
I don't know what you're saying!
我听不懂你…
I don't know what you...
不！
No! No!
喝悟汁！
Drink the ooze!
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi. Hi.
你把悟汁喝下去了吗？
Did you drink the ooze?
我怎么能听懂你说话？
Why can I understand you?
太好了 悟汁起效了
Great. That's the ooze.
大伙儿 起效了！悟汁起效了！
Hey, everybody, it worked! Ooze worked!
我们最终会成为朋友
We can finally be friends.
嗨 我叫维布
Hi. I am Veb.
你刚喝了我的汁
You just drank me.
我刚…什么？
I did... What?
要不要再喝点悟汁？来
Do you need some more ooze? Here.
-我帮你灌进这个洞洞… -不用了
-I can pour some ooze into your hole... -No, I'm okay.
-不用了 -哇哦
-I'm okay. I'm okay. -Oh, wow!
好大一个洞
A big hole.
你身上有几个洞洞？
How many holes do you have?
不好意思 这属于隐私吗？
I'm sorry. Is that a personal question?
我一个洞洞也没有
I don't have any holes.
他叫斯科特·朗
His name is Scott Lang.
他有七个洞洞
He has seven holes.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
你是怎么知道的？
How did you know that?
他叫夸兹 有心灵感应
He's Quaz. He's a telepath.
你会读心术？
You can read minds?
对 我真心希望我不会
Yeah, and I really wish I couldn't.
大家内心都好恶心
Everyone is disgusting.
-请你别想那种事好吗？ -抱歉
-Could you please stop thinking that? -Sorry.
-拜托你别这样 -别想？
-Please, stop. -Thinking?
-别想那种事 -我不想
-Thinking that. -I'm trying.
我看你挺想的 而且我也觉得你长得很怪
Well, not very hard. And I think you look weird too.
我没觉得你怪 我觉得你很酷
I don't think you look weird. I think you look really cool.
我也想脑袋冒红光
I wish my head glowed.
不 你不想
No, no, you don't.
我知道 我一紧张就管不住嘴
I know I don't. I'm nervous, okay? And it just came out.
你来这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
-你是间谍吗？ -什么？不是
-Are you a spy? -What? No. No, no.
我们应该拷问他
We should torture him.
朋友们 别紧张
Guys. No, it's okay.
我们不是间谍 他是我爸爸
We're not spies. He's my dad.
-谢谢 -不客气
-Thank you. -Welcome.
那旧金山是谁？
Then who is San Francisco?
-那是我们来的地方 -是个地方
-It's where we're from. -It's a place.
那地球又是什么？
Then what's Earth?
也是我们来的地方
It's also where we're from.
我们应该拷问他们
We should torture them.
你干嘛总想拷问别人？明明有别的办法
Why are you always trying to torture people? We have other options.
你的洞洞会流东西吗？比如乳汁 果汁
Do things come out of your holes, like milk, juice...
维布 别再好奇他的洞洞了
Veb, stop asking about his holes.
我们自己人也有洞洞
Some of us have holes.
你们到底是来干嘛的？
What are you doing here?
究竟是从哪儿来的？
Where are you from?
-冷静 -从上面来的
-Okay. -Up there. Up there.
-这地方上面有另一个宇宙 -从地球 大号的地球
-See, above this, it's a different universe. -The Earth. Big Earth.
-还是同一个宇宙 但是更大 -这儿也是地球 但是个很小的地球
-It's the same universe, but it's bigger. -This is Earth, but it's a very small Earth.
-有时候是这样 -我会变大变小
-Sometimes, I guess. -I get big. I shrink.
-就好比… -我还写了本书讲这事
-And it's like... -But I wrote a book about it, actually.
-又来了 -这儿是量子领域
-I don't know. -This is the Quantum Realm.
你必须缩小才能进入量子领域
You have to shrink to get in the Quantum Realm.
-我们缩小了 现在我们很小很小 -我们来的地方更大
-We shrunk. Right now, we're really small. -It's bigger where we're from.
-我们现在变小了 -那儿更大
-So, we're small right now. -It's bigger.
好吧 他们说的是真话
Okay, they're telling the truth.
是真是假不重要
It doesn't matter.
你们是从上面来的
You come from above.
跟他一样
Like him.
所以他一定在追捕你们
So, he is hunting you.
把这儿夷为平地也在所不惜
He will burn the world to find you.
谁？
Who?
征服者
The Conqueror.
这里居然有生物 还是智慧生物
There are beings down here. Intelligent beings.
我一直推测有这种可能 直到亲眼看见
I always theorized it was possible, but to be here...
一个亚原子宇宙
a subatomic universe.
这会颠覆我们对于生命的所有认知
This changes everything we know about life...
对于进化 我们在银河中的位置
evolution, our place in the galaxy...
天啊！
Holy shit!
他长得好像西兰花
That guy looks like broccoli.
低调点
Keep your head down.
跟紧我
Follow me.
把这个喝了
Drink those.
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
我来找凯拉
I'm here for Krylar.
是你
It's you.
别声张 你知道就行
Let's keep that between us.
还有凯拉
And Krylar.
你好
Hello.
我不懂你们的风土习俗
I don't know your ways or customs...
有没有什么喝的能让我一醉方休？
but I assume that you have a beverage that can get me drunk?
当然有 先生
Absolutely, sir.
美女为何独自买醉？
So, what's your story then?
天啊
God.
滚
Move.
该走了
It's time.
跟我来
Follow me.
这边请
Right this way.
你跟这个人怎么认识的？
How exactly do you know this guy?
他是我当自由战士时的老战友
Old freedom fighter friend of mine.
什么 你还当过自由战士？
Sorry, you were a freedom fighter?
或者说恐怖分子
Or terrorist.
这要看你问谁了
Depends on who you ask.
不过 相信我 他能帮我们
But, trust me, he can help.
珍妮·凡·戴恩？
Janet Van Dyne?
我还以为你死了呢
I thought you were dead.
好久不见 凯拉
Been a long time, Krylar.
我现在的正式头衔是凯拉阁下
Officially, Lord Krylar now.
我真不想大家这么叫我
I fought like hell against that.
听起来太自命不凡了
It sounds so elitist.
你一定就是汉克
You have got to be Hank.
我听过好多你和你蚂蚁的故事
I've heard so much about you and your ants.
话说蚂蚁到底是什么？
What are ants anyway?
我们这儿有吗？
Do we have 'em down here?
我觉得应该没有
I don't think so. No.
太可惜了
That's too bad.
霍普
Hope.
你一定是霍普了
You have to be Hope.
她以前每天都说起你
She talked about you every day.
奇怪了
That's strange...
她从来没说起过你
she never said anything about you.
换了我也不会跟孩子说
I don't think I would have told my kid either.
-太刺激了 -你真逗
-Wild stuff. -Funny.
有多刺激？
How wild?
非常刺激 亨利 真的
Very wild, Henry. Yeah.
凯拉 我们需要你帮忙
Krylar, we need your help.
珍妮 我们一起经历了那么多事
Janet, after all we've been through, together...
尽管开口
just ask me.
要我怎么帮你？
Tell me, how can I help?
但首先…
But...
你们饿不饿？我快饿死了
is anyone starving? I'm starving.
小伙子
Boys...
上菜
Now.
他们一无所知
They don't know anything.
什么都不知道
About... anything.
那就送他们离开
Then get them out of here.
不好意思
Excuse me.
听着 他说得对 我不清楚你们的情况
Look, he's right. I don't know what's going on.
我们只想找到家人
We're just trying to find our family.
你有地图吗？
Do you have a map?
我们只想回…
All we wanna do is go...
等等 别开枪
Wait, wait. Don't shoot.
是自己人
They're with us.
这房子是活的？
Is that building alive?
你们的是死的？
Yours are dead?
等等 不好意思
Look. Excuse me.
我们只想回家
We just wanna go home.
至少你们还有家可回
At least you still have a home.
这儿发生了什么？
What happened here?
征服者摧毁了我们的家园
The Conqueror burned our homes.
我们的文明
Our stories.
在我们同胞的尸骨堆上建起他的要塞
He built his citadel on the bones of our people.
有些人逃了出来
Some of us escaped...
路上又遇见其他人
found others on the run.
我们集结所有可用战力
We gathered who we could to fight.
但还远远不够
It was never enough.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我们能帮忙
We can help.
-凯茜… -爸爸 你可是复仇者
-Cassie... -Dad, you're an Avenger.
他们需要帮助
They need help.
不 我需要做的是带你回家
No. What I need to do is get you home.
你为什么不肯帮忙？
Why don't you wanna help?
我们根本不了解这个地方
We don't know anything about this place.
都不知道这儿的时间是怎么流动的
I mean, I don't even know how time works down here.
上面的世界是过了十秒
Have we been gone for 10 seconds?
还是已经过了十年？
Or have we been gone for 10 years?
想想你妈妈
Think about your mom right now.
-你能想象她该有… -别拿妈妈当借口
-Can you imagine what she must be... -Don't use Mom as an excuse.
-你就是不在乎 -不 我在乎
-You just don't care. -No, I do care.
我知道你想帮助别人
I know you wanna help. I do.
但这不是我们该打的仗
But this is not our fight.
坏事没落到你头上 不代表天下太平
Just 'cause it's not happening to you doesn't mean it's not happening.
嘿
Hey.
看着我好吗？
Would you look at me?
她对你很失望
She's disappointed in you.
我知道 谢谢
I got that. Yeah. Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
这事我们晚点再谈
We'll talk about it later.
现在得先找到他们三个
Right now, let's just find the others.
只有珍妮最了解这个地方
No one knows this place better than Janet.
你刚说什么？
What did you say?
什么？
What?
那个名字
That name.
珍妮·凡·戴恩
Janet Van Dyne.
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
我们也在找她 你认识她？
That's what we're trying to find out. You know her?
认识
I know her.
她不该来这儿
She shouldn't be here.
嘿 麻烦来几杯醒酒水
Hey, bring a round of the chasers, please.
好的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
如果你们没喝过这个 那不建议尝试
If you haven't had this, don't try it...
它会颠覆你们的人生
unless you want to change your life.
凯拉 我们在找朋友
Krylar, we're looking for friends of ours.
两个人
Two of them.
跟我们一样都是人类
Human, like us.
人类 就是这词
Human, that's the word.
我都忘了你们上面的人管自己叫什么了
Totally forgot what you call yourselves up there.
人类
Human.
你不是人类吗？
Are you not human?
不严格来说 我是
Not technically, but yes.
在关键时刻
In the ways that matter.
不！
No!
让我们谈谈
Let us talk.
是什么风把你吹来了 珍妮？
So, what is it that brings you to us, Janet?
我没记错的话 当初是你要离开
If I remember correctly, you left.
丢下我们所有人
You left all of us.
跟他一起
With him.
珍妮 他在说什么？
Janet, what is he talking about?
你没跟他们说他的事
You didn't tell them about him.
你跟他们提过
Did you say anything...
你在这儿干的事吗？
about what you did here?
有多少人因你而死？
How many people died because of you?
你的家人知道你是什么人吗？
Does your family even know who you are?
你妈妈
Your mommy...
充满秘密
is full of secrets.
你撒谎
You're lying.
我撒谎
I lie.
还真不少
A lot.
但这件事上没有
Not about this.
放他们走
Let them go.
他只想要我
He just wants me.
可你想保住他们
But you want them.
所以他们也得来
So they're coming too.
还有你那两个朋友
Along with those other friends of yours.
我听到他们的消息了
I heard about them.
但他也听到了
But he did too.
已经派出了追捕者
And he sent the Hunter.
什么样的追捕者？
What kind of hunter?
既不是人也不是机器
Not a man. Not a machine.
而是一种机械化生命体 专为…
A mechanized organism designed only...
杀戮而生
for killing.
他们在哪儿？
Where are they?
不清楚
No clue.
死了
Dead.
估计死了
Probably dead.
太遗憾了 这一切
This is so sad when all of this...
本来可以避免 珍妮
could have been avoided, Janet.
他要什么给他就是了
Just give him what he wants.
你怎么会变成这样？
What happened to you?
我们并肩对抗过他
We fought against him.
他能让你不得不服
He can be very persuasive.
去见见他吧
Let's pay him a visit.
我们结束了
I think we're done here.
那艘飞船能带我们离开吗？
Can that ship get us out of here?
掩护我？
Cover me?
一如既往
Always.
亨利 你去操纵
Henry, take the helm.
我来点火
I'm gonna hot-wire this thing.
操纵杆在哪儿？
Where are the controls?
那两坨就是
Those are the controls.
什么鬼？
What the hell?
你能行的 就当骑自行车
You'll be great. It's like flying a bike.
这自行车是活的？
Is the bike alive?
手伸到底！
Hands, all the way in!
像往火鸡里塞馅料
Like stuffing a turkey.
-不是吧 就他？ -他以前很有魅力
-Really, him? -He used to be charming.
就那家伙？
That guy?
我在这儿待了三十年 亨利
I was down here for 30 years, Henry.
-我有需求 -天啊
-I had needs. -Oh, my God.
我理解 我也有需求
Look, I get it. I've got needs too.
饶了我吧！
Oh, my God!
我跟别人约过几顿饭
I had dinner with someone a few times.
她叫琳达
Her name was Linda.
最后没成
It didn't work out.
为什么没成？
What went wrong?
因为她不是你 宝贝
She wasn't you, baby.
-叫所有人上船 准备转移 -好
-Get everyone in the ships. We're leaving. -All right.
-左伦 -在
-And, Xolum. -Right here.
送他们走 越远越好
Take them as far away from here as you can.
-为什么？ -什么？
-Why? -What?
如果你们在找珍妮 那他一定在找你们
If you're looking for Janet, he's looking for you.
你把他们引到这儿来了
You led them straight to us.
快走
Come on, come on.
尽量多带些人走
Take as many as you can.
我们拖住敌人
We'll hold them off.
快跑！
Go!
快点！快跑！
Come on! Hurry, hurry!
得赶紧离开！
We gotta go! We gotta go!
快上船！
Get on. Get on now!
得马上离开！
We have to go now. Now!
天啊！
Oh, my God!
凯茜 快走！
Cassie, let's go!
去避难所
Get to the sanctuary.
等我消息
Wait for my message.
-维布 得走了 -不 等等！
-Veb, we're leaving. -No. No, wait!
-快上去！ -我的朋友们
-Move! Move! -All my friends.
交出旅行者
Give up the travelers.
征服者会宽赦你们
The Conqueror will show you mercy.
我领教过他的宽赦
I know his mercy.
待在这儿 我…
Stay here. I'm...
凯茜？
Cassie?
坏了
Oh, no.
我坦白 我有战衣
Okay. I have a suit.
对 我发现了
Yeah, I noticed.
-没事吧？ -没事
-You okay? -Yes.
听好 借势发力 懂吗？
Look, momentum, right?
飞身一击 懂吗？ 一气呵成 飞身一击
Jump, tap, right? One move. Jump, tap.
我知道怎么做 爸爸
I know how to do it, Dad.
-你知道？真的吗？ -是的
-Do you? Really? -Yes.
我看着可不像
'Cause it didn't look like it from my end.
我没掐准时间
I messed up on the timing.
飞身…
Jump...
像这样
Like that.
看见我刚才的动作了吗？
You see what I did? You see what I did?
没有 你刚就这么点大
No. You're like this small.
我飞身一击了
I jumped and tapped.
詹托拉 得走了
Jentorra, we have to go.
上飞船！
Get to the ship!
欢迎回到量子领域 斯科特
Welcome back to the Quantum Realm, Scott.
我等这一刻很久了
I've been waiting a long time for this.
什么？
What?
有人在里面吗？
Is someone in there?
当然
Oh, yes.
我是你逃不开的宿命
The destiny you cannot escape.
我们的命运早已被绑在一起
Our fates have always been forged together...
从我们相遇那天起
ever since that day we met.
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
坏人快走开！
Get away from us!
那天你将我重创
The day you broke me.
-把我打落到这里 -等等
-Banished me down here. -Wait.
达伦？
Darren?
见到我意不意外？
Surprised to see me?
是的
Yeah.
是那个蜜蜂男？
It's the bee guy?
-是那个蜜蜂男？ -凯茜？
-It's the bee guy? -Cassie?
我差点没认出你
I almost didn't recognize you.
你怎么活下来的？
How are you not dead?
我变成了终极武器
I became the ultimate weapon.
你这造型是终极武器？
That's what this is?
听着 达伦
Look, Darren.
达伦已经死了！
Darren is dead!
这里只有魔多客！
There is only M.O.D.O.K.!
你已经无路可逃了 斯科特
And there's no place you can run, Scott.
逃不过我
Not from me.
更逃不出他的掌心
And not from him.
他是未来
He's the future.
也是过去
He's the past.
现在他需要的就是你
And now all he needs is you.
妈妈？
Mom?
谁要抓斯科特和凯茜？
What's after Scott and Cassie?
我们得去找他们
We have to find them.
我得先办些其它事
There's something I have to do first.
他们可能会没命的！
They could be dead!
霍普 冷静
Hope, please.
你到现在还有事瞒着我们
And you're still hiding things from us.
我是为了保护你们不受伤害
I am trying to protect you.
受什么伤害？
From what?
谁让你这么害怕？
Who are you so afraid of?
你第三次进大牢吧？
Third time in jail?
我第四次
Four.
我们又相会了
And here we are again.
面对面
Face to face.
这一面
That's a face.
真是好大一面
It's a big face.
你为什么就剩个脑袋飘着？
Why are you just a floating head?
要不你给我们讲讲 达伦
Maybe you could walk us through this, Darren.
你把达伦丢在量子领域等死
You left Darren to die in the Quantum Realm.
但征服者发现了我
But the Conqueror found me.
赐我新生
Rebuilt me.
将我打造成终极武器
Made me the ultimate weapon.
一个机械化生命体 专为杀戮…
A mechanized organism designed only for...
魔多客？
M.O.D.O.K.?
我懂了 是首字母缩写
I get it. It's an acronym.
是简称
It's an acronym.
机械化生命体 专为杀戮而生
Mechanized organism designed only for killing.
应该简称魔多夫客
Actually, that's M.O.D.O.F.K.
-你一定以为再也见不到我了 -我才发现你的腿好像小宝宝
-I bet you thought you'd seen the last of me. -Just now noticing the baby legs.
才不像小宝宝
They're not baby legs.
你好像婴儿背带
A little bit like a Björn.
你以为自己很聪明是吗？
You think you're so smart.
斯科特·朗 你夺走了我的一切
Scott Lang, the man who took everything from me.
偷走了我的人生
Who stole my whole life.
但我报仇了
But I did it.
我抓到你们了
I got you here.
我发现了你的信号 凯茜
I found your signal, Cassie.
这事还得谢谢你 不然我不可能成功
Thanks for that, by the way. Couldn't have done it without you.
你们眼前这个人摆脱了束缚
You're looking at a man set free.
我在这里创造的成果多到你想不到
I've created so much more here than you could possibly imagine.
全都献给他
All for him.
被困在量子领域的不止我一个
I wasn't the only one stranded in the Quantum Realm.
这儿是什么地方？
What is this place?
他说他是一个旅行者
He said he was a traveler.
一名科学家 飞船偏航坠落到这儿
A scientist who crashed off course.
他有一艘飞船
He had a ship...
是我从未见过的科技
beyond anything I had ever seen.
一艘能够穿梭多元宇宙的飞船
A ship that could travel the Multiverse.
多元宇宙？
The Multiverse?
你是说交替维度？
As in alternate dimensions?
平行现实？
Parallel realities?
我刚开始也不信
I didn't believe it at first.
但确实是真的
But it's real.
就跟我们的推论一样
Just like we theorized.
这艘船能送我们回去吗？
Can this take us home?
它能送你去任何地方
It can take you anywhere.
我从没见过像他那样的人
I'd never met anyone like him.
他好像彻底…
He felt so...
迷失了
lost.
可能我们都是
I guess we both were.
但我们找到了出路
But we had a way out.
我们试了各种方法
We tried everything...
给飞船的动力核心充能
to recharge his ship's energy core.
都失败了
Nothing worked.
但孤单了那么多年 能多个朋友我也知足了
But after so many years alone, it was nice to have a friend.
我骗了霍普
I lied to Hope.
跟她说我会回去
I told her I was coming home.
我仿佛能看见她站在门口
I can see her by the door.
等我回家
Waiting for me.
我做的最后一件事
That's the last thing I did...
就是骗了她
was lie to her.
我总以为还有很多时间
I just thought I'd have more time.
我可以给你
I can give that to you.
时间
Time.
时间不像你们想的那样
It's not what you think it is.
它是一个牢笼
It's a cage.
会用尽一切办法
And it does everything it can...
打垮你
to break you.
直到你挣脱出来才发现
It's not until you free yourself from it that you see...
它本质上
just how small...
是多么的渺小
it always was.
我们一定能离开这里
We're going to get out of here.
她打开门就会看见
She's gonna open the door...
你在门外
and you'll be there.
我保证
I promise.
-干活吧 -好
-Let's get to work. -Okay.
我们花了很长时间 终于成功了
It took ages, but we did it.
飞船起死回生了
We brought it back to life.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
飞船是用神经驱动的
His ship was neurokinetic.
与他的思维相连
Connected to his thoughts.
触摸到飞船时
When I touched it...
我看见了他的内心
I saw his mind.
感受到了…
I felt...
他所做的一切
what he had done.
一个又一个世界
Entire worlds...
一条又一条时间线
entire timelines.
化为乌有 好像从未存在过
Gone, like they never even existed.
珍妮？
Janet?
我们可以走了
We can leave.
马上
Right now.
康是谁？
Who is Kang?
是我必须扮演的角色
Who I need to be.
他不是意外坠落
He didn't crash here.
而是被流放到这儿的
He was exiled here.
独立于时间和空间之外
Outside space and time.
只有这里
The only place...
才困得住他
that could hold him.
被流放？
Exiled?
被谁？
By who?
不知道
I don't know.
但他们毁了他的飞船
But they sabotaged his ship.
把他困在了这儿
And trapped him here.
结果因为我
And because of me...
他就要逃脱了
he was getting out.
珍妮？
Janet?
别靠近我
Stay away.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
我向你保证过
I made a promise.
让我送你回家吧
Just let me take you home.
然后呢？
And then?
你打算干什么？
What are you going to do?
赢
Win.
我说过 时间不是你们想的那样
I told you time isn't what you think.
我可以改变时间
I can make it...
让你从未离开过她
so you never left her.
霍普打开门就会看见
Hope is going to open the door...
你在门外
and you'll be there.
你出去以后
And how many worlds will die...
会有多少个世界被毁灭？
if you get out?
你的不会
Not yours.
她永远不会知道
She'll never know.
你不想再见到你女儿吗？
Don't you want to see your daughter again?
我不能放你走
I can't let you leave.
你凭什么觉得你能拦住我？
Why do you think you can stop me?
把它给我 珍妮
Give it to me, Janet.
给我！
Give it to me!
我打不过他 他太强大了
I couldn't beat him. He was too powerful.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
对不起 霍普
I'm sorry, Hope.
不！
No!
我炸开了动力核心
I blew up his core.
把他跟时间彻底隔绝
Cut him off from time.
也把我们永远隔绝在了这儿
And trapped us both down here forever.
但我还是给了他足够的力量
But I gave him back enough.
现在他取回了战衣
Now that he had his suit back...
变回了他一直以来的角色
he became what he always was.
征服者
A conqueror.
他掌握的科技和武器
He's got weapons and technology...
再过几百年我们也望尘莫及
centuries beyond anything we can dream of.
他将他的牢笼变成了他的帝国
He took his prison and made it his empire.
我花了许多时间与他斗争
I spent years fighting him...
逃离追捕 四处躲藏
running from him, hiding from him.
后来你们救了我
And then you saved me.
带我回了家
You brought me home.
但我并不配拥有这些
But I didn't deserve it.
我放出了一头怪物在这儿横行
I unleashed a monster on this place...
然后逃跑了
and ran away.
珍妮 这种事谁也想不到
Janet, you couldn't have known.
对不起 一直没告诉你们
I'm sorry I never told you.
我太想忘掉这一切了
I just wanted to forget.
我只想重新做回你的妈妈
I just wanted to be your mom again.
对不起 让你一个人承受了那么多
I'm so sorry you had to go through all of that alone.
但你现在不是一个人了
But you are not alone now.
我们一起打败他
We'll stop him together.
他想夺回核心
He's after the core.
他需要皮姆粒子才能靠近核心
But he needs Pym Particles to reach it.
他抓到斯科特和凯茜就有皮姆粒子了
And if he's got Scott and Cassie, he's got Pym Particles.
-还抢先了一步 -没错
-And a head start. -Exactly.
-得赶紧行动了 -霍普
-We gotta get out of here. -Hope.
决不能让他逃出去
He cannot get out.
你很有意思
You're an interesting man...
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are...
但你犯了个大错
but you've made a big mistake.
懂吗？
Okay?
我可是复仇者
I'm an Avenger.
我已经呼叫了其他复仇者
I've called the other Avengers...
你是复仇者？
You're an Avenger?
我杀过你吗？
Have I killed you before?
什么？
What?
时间一长就记不清了
They all blur together after a while.
你不是那个拿锤子的吧？
You're not the one with the hammer?
那是索尔
No, that's Thor.
经常有人搞错
We get confused a lot.
我们身材差不多 你是谁？
Similar body types. Who are you?
只是一个…
Just a man...
失去了大把时间的人
who's lost a lot of time.
跟你一样
Like you.
但我们可以联手找回来
But we can help each other with that.
魔多客说你擅长偷盗
M.O.D.O.K. tells me you're a good thief.
没错 他偷了我的东西
Yeah, he stole something from me.
我在的时候 没你说话的份
Do not speak when I am in the room.
说真的 珍妮比你有用多了
Gotta say, Janet was a lot more helpful.
你也认识珍妮？
You know Janet too?
这儿的人是不是都认识珍妮？
Does everyone down here know Janet?
她没跟你们提过我？
She didn't tell you about me?
倒也不算意外
I guess that's not a surprise.
珍妮偷了我的东西
Janet stole something from me.
我离开这儿的船票
My ticket out of here.
只有你能帮我偷回来
And you're the only one who can steal it back.
我为什么要帮你？
And why would I do that?
因为你们想离开这儿
Because you want to get out of here.
而我必须离开这儿
And I need to get out of here.
因为我清楚结局
Because I know how it ends.
什么的结局？
How what ends?
万事万物
All of it.
时间于我不是一条直线
I don't live in a straight line.
手握时间
And with time...
你很难
it's hard...
忍住不跳到结局
not to skip to the end.
如果你们想阻止接下来的灾难
So, if you want to stop what's coming...
相信我
and trust me...
你们想
you do...
我是你们唯一的机会
I am the only shot you have.
什么灾难？
What's coming?
我
Me.
很多个我
A lot of me.
他们把我流放到这儿
They exiled me, down here.
因为他们怕我
They're afraid of me.
但只有我能让你们回去
But I'm the man who can get you home.
那就这么说定了？
So, do we have a deal?
我觉得我们定不了
No, I don't think we do.
爸爸！
Dad!
我帮你省点工夫
Let me make this easy for you.
把我要的东西带来
You will bring me what I need...
不然我就当面杀了你女儿
or I will kill your daughter in front of you...
然后再让你重温那一刻
then make you relive that moment...
一遍又一遍 无穷无尽
over and over again in time, endlessly...
直到你求我杀了你
until you beg me to kill you.
听明白了吗？
Do we understand?
别动她
Don't do this.
我喜欢跟明白人打交道
I'm a man who likes to be understood.
爸爸
Dad.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
不！住手！
No! No!
听着 这事可以商量
Look, we can talk about this.
别照他说的做！
Don't do it!
你真的应该照我说的做
You really should do it.
拜托
Please.
放过我女儿 求你
That's my daughter, please.
你想让她活还是想让她死？
Do you want her to live, or do you want her to die?
求求你！
Please!
你觉得我在骗你？
You think I'm lying?
你看我像是会骗人的人吗？
Do I look like a liar to you?
住手！
Stop!
-爸爸！ -我答应你
-Dad! -I'll do it. I'll do it.
我答应 放了她
I'll do it. Just let her go.
放了她！
Let her go. Let her go!
你真的差远了
You're out of your league.
蚁人
Ant-Man.
该庆幸你还有利用价值
Just be glad I need you.
不许再碰她
Don't touch her again.
那就把我要的东西带来
Then give me what I need.
东西在哪儿？
Where is it?
那是什么？
What is that?
原本是多元宇宙飞船动力核心
It was a multiversal engine core.
有了它你就能在时空中任意穿梭
A power source that can take you anywhere in space and time.
后来被珍妮炸了
Then Janet blew it up.
核心在那里面？
It's in that?
那就是核心
It is that.
我们得想办法进到中心
And we have to get to the center.
谢谢告知
That's good to know.
你要缩小然后穿过暴风中心
You'll have to shrink down and pass through the eye of the storm.
进去找到核心以后
Once you're inside, find the core...
把它变回原来的大小
and size it back down.
它长什么样？
What does it look like?
要偷东西总得知道长什么样吧
When I steal something, I usually know what I'm stealing.
你见到就知道了
You'll know it when you see it.
快去快回别耽搁
Get in and out as fast as you can.
在里面待久了 精神会逐渐崩溃
The longer you're in there, the more your mind will come undone.
抓紧时间
Better hurry.
爸爸！
Dad!
对不起
I'm sorry.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
不是
No.
我失败了
I messed up.
凯茜
Cassie.
我整个人生都建立在失败上
My whole life happened because I messed up.
我唯一成功的事就是你
The only thing I didn't mess up is you.
爸爸！
Dad!
没事的
It's okay.
别担心
我爱你 小花生
I love you, Peanut.
我也爱你
I love you too.
好了 我进来了
Okay. I'm in.
达伦 能听见吗？
Darren, can you hear me?
达伦？
Darren?
魔多客 能听见吗？
M.O.D.O.K., can you hear me?
干嘛？
What?
-我进来了 -好的
-I'm in. -Okay.
好 接下来干嘛？有什么计划？
Okay, so what do I do? What's the plan?
别死了？
Don't die?
谢谢 帮大忙了 魔多客
Thanks. Big help, M.O.D.O.K.
看见它了吗？
Do you see it?
对 看见了
Yeah. I see it.
我要进去了
I'm heading in.
什么鬼？
What the hell?
我说过 斯科特 进去只是第一步
I told you, Scott. Getting in was just the beginning.
你没说过
You never said that.
我为什么会看见另一个我？
Why am I looking at another me?
我不是另一个 你才是另一个
I'm not another me. You're another me.
你刚冒出来…
You just came out...
我为什么会看见另一个我？
Why am I looking at another me?
那是你的另一种可能性
You're looking at the possibility of another you.
你进入了可能性风暴
You're in a Probability Storm.
这到底是什么意思？
What does any of that mean?
-你不知道？ -我为什么会知道？
-You don't know? -Why would I know?
因为是你把我弄来的
Because you got me in here.
所以我是真的 对吧？
So, I am the real one, huh?
不 我没那么说
No. I didn't say that.
-什么鬼？ -什么鬼？
-What the hell? -What the hell?
-等等 -什么鬼？
-Wait. Wait, wait. -What the hell?
什么鬼？
What the hell?
这儿是什么地方？
What is this place?
你在可能性风暴里
It's a Probability Storm.
你可能做的每个选择都同时存在
Every choice you could make, existing all at once.
他说什么？
What is he saying? What's he saying?
-他说什么？ -那里就像薛定谔的盒子
-What's he saying? -You're inside Schrödinger's box.
而你是那只猫
And you're the cat.
-什么乱七八糟的 -我懂了
-That doesn't make sense. -Oh, I get it.
都别动！听见没？都别动！
Nobody move! All right? Nobody move!
我们干嘛听你的？你压根都不是真的
Why should we listen to you? You're not even the real one.
-什么鬼？ -我是真的吗？
-What the hell? -Am I real?
-我是真的吗？ -我是真的吗？
-Am I real? -Am I real?
-我是真的！ -什么鬼？
-I am the real one! -What the hell?
什么鬼 我才是真的
What the hell. I'm the real one.
朋友们 别激动
Guys. Hey, relax.
冷静点 深呼吸
Take it easy. Breathe.
会有办法的 大家一起想
We'll figure this out. Together.
你是谁？
Who are you?
为什么穿成这样？
Why are you dressed like that?
因为我在芭斯罗缤上班
Because I work at Baskin-Robbins.
这是我的工服
This is my uniform.
这是正常人穿的衣服
These are normal clothes.
你们为什么穿成这样？
Why are you dressed like that?
-有冰激凌么？ -别吵了！
-Do you have ice cream? -Enough!
直接干！
Let's do this!
我们都死定了
Oh, we're all gonna die.
等等
Wait.
等等！
Wait. Wait!
不！
No! No!
不！等等！
No! Wait! No!
我收到斯科特的信号了
I've got a read on Scott.
别挡我的路
Out of the way!
-妈妈 这是什么情况？ -你干什么？
-Mom! What is this? -What are you doing?
别去看 她们只是可能性
Don't look at them. They're just possibilities.
不是真的你
They're not you.
斯科特 你在哪儿？
Scott, where are you?
我怎么会在这儿？
Why am I here?
别担心 这次一定行
Don't worry. It'll work this time.
你想…等等 别去
What are you... Wait, wait, no, no. Stop.
-停下！不！ -大家看我的
-Stop! No! -I got this, guys.
交给我！我能行！
I got this! I got it!
斯科特 你在哪儿？
Scott, where are you?
斯科特！
Scott!
你在哪儿 斯科特？
Where are you, Scott?
-我不能呼吸了 -你勒我脖子了
-I can't breathe. -Ow, that's my neck.
别踢我！
Stop kicking me!
-我的背! -我们都要死了！
-My back! -We're all gonna die!
爸爸
Dad.
快回来
Come back.
爸爸
Dad...
如果你能听见
if you can hear me...
求求你回来 快回来
come back. Just come back.
-不要放弃 -加油
-Don't give up. -Come on.
-爸爸 求你再回来一次 -加油
-Dad, just come back one more time. -Come on.
-她需要我们 -拜托
-She needs us. -Please.
-加油 -回来 -她需要我们 大家齐心协力
-Yes, come on. -Come back. -She needs us. Let's do it together.
-拉他上去 -拉住他
-Get him up! Get him up! -Grab him! Grab him!
加油
Let's go.
-加油 托他上去！ -很好！
-Come on, lift him! -Yes!
-我托着你！去吧 -加油 就是这样
-I got ya, I got ya! Go. -Come on. That's it.
-加油！ -推他一把！
-Come on! -Give him a boost! Give him a boost!
加油 为了凯茜！大家加油！
Come on, we're doing it for Cassie! Fellas, let's go!
大家齐心协力！
Everyone together!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你是怎么做到的？
How are you able to do that?
我来告诉你
I'll tell you how.
因为我们有同一个目标
We all want the same thing.
我来了 凯茜
And I'm coming, Cassie.
去找她吧 哥儿们
Go get her, pal.
大家加把劲！
Everyone, let's go!
加油！
Come on!
加油 再靠近点
Come on, closer.
再高点！
Get him higher!
大家坚持住
Hang on, guys, hang on.
小心 稳住
Careful. Steady, steady.
稳住 就是这样
Steady. That's it.
上吧
Let's go.
什么？
What?
-糟了 -怎么了？成功了吗？
-Oh no. -What happened? Did it work?
对不起 兄弟！
Sorry, buddy!
-不 -不要
-No. -No.
霍普 你是真的吗？
Hope, are you real?
我是真的
I'm real.
那我们一起上
Then let's do this.
准备好了吗？
You ready?
好了
Ready.
走吧
Come on.
得赶紧带它离开
We gotta get that thing out of here.
不行 等等
No, no, no. Wait.
凯茜在他手上
He's got Cassie.
-什么？ -斯科特
-What? -Scott.
-珍妮 -把东西给我
-Janet. -Give that to me.
-得赶紧走了 -不行
-We have to go now. -No.
凯茜在他手上
He's got Cassie.
我们会救她的 我保证一定会的
We will save her. I promise you we will save her...
你决不能把这个给他
but you cannot give that to him.
换我就不会信她
I wouldn't trust her.
珍妮的心思…
Janet has a way of...
总是变来变去
changing her mind.
你好 小糖豆
Hello, Jellybean.
那么
So...
你打算怎么做 斯科特？
what's it gonna be, Scott?
瞧瞧
Well, well.
这不是我曾经的好老师吗？
If it isn't my old mentor.
嗨 汉克
Hi, Hank.
达伦？
Darren?
没想到还会再见到你的徒弟…
Didn't expect to see your protégé again after all...
我的妈呀 达伦
Holy shit, Darren.
你这是怎么了？
What happened to you?
我是终极武器！
I'm the ultimate weapon!
要我亲自动手吗？
Do I need to take it?
我女儿在哪儿？
Where is my daughter?
斯科特
Scott.
不要
Don't.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
没有你 她也没事
She'll be fine without you.
永别了 汉克
So long, Hank.
亨利
Henry.
当初你把我丢在这儿等死
You left me right here to die.
这次轮到他们了
Let's see how they do.
你看到了什么？
What did you see?
上次我们都没机会聊这事
We didn't really get a chance to talk about it last time.
我一直很想知道
But I always wondered.
你接触到我的内心时
When you touched my mind...
看到了什么？
what did you see?
一个怪物
A monster...
却自以为是神
who thinks he's a god.
等你也能像我一样看透时间
When you can see time the way I do...
你就没法视而不见了
you don't get to close your eyes.
这世上就只有你能看透吗？
And you're the only one who sees?
只有我看出来它崩坏了
I am the only one that can see it's broken.
是谁破坏的？
And who broke it?
是我
I did.
每一个世界的我
Every version of me.
我的变体
My variants.
在多元宇宙中
Throughout the Multiverse.
像孩子一样玩弄时间
Playing with time, like children.
但我看到了结局
But I saw how it ends.
我看到他们带来的混乱
I saw their chaos...
蔓延到各个世界
spreading across realities.
宇宙相互碰撞
Universes colliding.
侵袭无休无止
Endless incursions.
我看到多元宇宙
I saw the Multiverse.
正在走向灭亡
And it was dying.
他们就是元凶
All because of them.
于是我出手接管了
So, I took control.
你是说你发动了战争
You mean you started a war.
现在你想把所有威胁到你的宇宙都消灭
And now you wanna wipe away any universe that's a threat to you.
只有怪物会这么做
That's what monsters do.
这是征服者的职责
That's what conquerors do.
把崩坏的世界销毁
They burn the broken world.
然后创造一个新世界
And they make a new one.
你不是想拯救世界拯救生命
You don't care about saving anything or anyone.
你只是想报仇 因为他们打败了你
You only want revenge because they beat you.
因为你输了
Because you lost.
我岂止是输了
I have lost.
你根本想象不出我失去了什么
You have no idea what I have lost.
我要把他们从所有时间线上抹杀
And I will burn them out of time...
让他们血债血偿
for what they've done to me.
你这么做会抹消整条整条的时间线
You'll be wiping out entire timelines.
杀死不计其数的生命
Murdering trillions of people.
可惜那不重要 珍妮
I wish that mattered, Janet.
天啊 我在干嘛？
Oh, God. What am I doing?
什么？
What?
汉克！
Hank!
这是你的蚂蚁吗？
Are these your ants?
你养的那些？
From the ant farm?
对 斯科特 它们是我的蚂蚁
Yes, Scott, they're my ants.
你怎么找到它们的？
How did you find them down here?
掉下来后 我一直收到奇怪的信号
I've been picking up strange signals ever since we crashed.
起初我以为是出了故障
First I thought maybe it was a malfunction.
受到了干扰
Some kind of interference.
这是什么声音？
What is that?
但我错了
But it wasn't.
是蚂蚁
It was the ants.
一直在试着联系我
They were reaching out the whole time.
它们应该是穿过了某种时间膨胀区域
Apparently, they passed through some sort of time dilation.
在一天之内度过了数千年的岁月
They've lived thousands of years in a single day...
不断扩充知识 科学技术
expanding their knowledge, their science...
达到了我从未想过的先进水平
becoming more advanced than I could have ever thought.
我没找到它们
I didn't find them.
是它们找到了我
They found me.
我就说它们很聪明
I told you they were smart.
它们建立了一种类似技术主义的二级文明
They've already built something of a technocratic Class-Two civilization.
我知道社会主义这个词容易引起争议
I mean, I know socialism is a charged word...
-但我们能从它们身上学到很多… -爸爸
-but we could learn a lot from these... -Dad.
对 它们是我的蚂蚁
Yeah, they're my ants.
蚂蚁永不言弃
And ants don't give up.
我不管他是谁
I don't care who this guy is.
不管他有什么能耐
I don't care what he can do.
我要去救凯茜
I'm getting Cassie.
我们怎么才能扭转劣势打败康？
So, how do we even the odds against Kang?
我们想到了几个办法
We've got some ideas.
什么办法？
What are you thinking?
引用某位大作家的话
Well, as a great writer once said...
成长的空间永远都有
"There's always room to grow."
你看了我的书？
You read my book?
一句废话都没落下
Every goddamn word.
来吧 该干活了
Come on. Let's go to work.
嘿！对不起
Hey! I'm sorry.
我是不是吓到你了
That was probably terrifying.
你来干什么？
What are you doing here?
我来救你
I'm rescuing you.
怎么救？
How?
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
这玩意儿有钥匙吗？
Does this thing have like a key?
或是门卡 房卡之类的？
Or a card? Like a room key?
就是类似…
Do you know, like a...
见鬼！
Shit!
飞身一击
Jump and tap.
詹托拉
Jentorra.
对不起 连累你们吃苦头
I'm sorry I got your people hurt.
有什么我能帮忙的？
How can I help?
厉害
Wow.
让他们也吃吃苦头
Let's hurt 'em back.
天 你太酷了
Damn, you're cool.
你有计划吗？
Do you have a plan?
救你出去就是我的计划
Freeing you was basically my plan.
你有计划吗？
Do you have a plan?
要通知外面那些还能战斗的人
We need to get a message out to anyone who can still fight.
然后救出被关在下面牢房里的同胞
Then free our people from the detention cells below...
从敌人内部发起反攻
and launch a counteroffensive from within.
很好 你有计划 要怎么通知外面的人？
Yeah, you have a plan. So, how do we get a message out?
跟我来
Follow me.
好的 太棒了
Okay. Great.
我在这里建起了一座帝国 珍妮
I built an empire down here, Janet.
它将随我一起出征
And I'm taking it with me.
你当初真该抓住机会让我走
You really should've let me out when you had the chance.
历史不是纸笔写成的
History is not written.
是行动铸成的
It is forged.
今天我们向上进发
Today, we ascend.
从这座要塞出发 我将向那些把我流放的人复仇
From this fortress, I will take my revenge on those who banished me.
今天我们征服永恒
Today we conquer eternity.
康的时代将…
And the dynasty of Kang shall...
喂？能听见吗？
Hello? Is this working?
凯茜
Cassie?
这算开了还是没开？
I can't tell if this is working.
好了 应该开了
Okay. I think we're on.
我拖住敌人 你跟他们说
I'll hold them off. Get the message out.
不应该你跟他们说吗？
I thought you were getting the message out.
快！
Now!
我们在主塔 打开了防守突破口
We're inside. We breached the tower.
詹托拉跟我在一起
And I'm with Jentorra.
他不是不可战胜的
He's not invincible.
我知道你们可能觉得…
I know it might feel like...
已经太晚了
it's too late...
好像不管做什么都没用
like all we do is just lose.
但我失散的亲人
But the family I've lost...
教我要战斗到底
taught me to keep fighting.
要是他们在这儿也一定会战斗
And if they were here, they would too.
我们不能忽视小人物
We need to look out for the little guy.
这是我爸爸教我的
My dad taught me that.
当人们需要帮助时
'Cause when people needed help...
他没有袖手旁观
he didn't look the other way.
我们也一样
And neither do we.
得走了！
We need to move!
到主塔来！奋起反击！
Come to the tower! Fight back!
我知道你们一直在等 现在就是反击的时候
I know you've been waiting. Now is the time to strike.
他知道自己不可能战胜所有人
He knows he can't take all of us.
快到…
Come to the...
凯茜
Cassie.
我追踪到信号了 妈妈肯定也在那儿
I think I found the signal. Mom's gotta be there, too.
-我们走 -我开船
-Let's go. -I'll drive.
找到朗的女儿
Find Lang's daughter.
杀了她
Kill her.
快出来！
Let's go. Let's go!
想战斗的人跟我走！
If you want to fight, follow me!
到此为止了 凯茜
It's over, Cassie.
去救其他人 快走！
Free the others. Go!
他会看见我们过来
He's gonna see us coming.
对 就是要让他看见
Yeah. I'll make sure of it.
开始启动
Begin the launch.
你爸爸没来 凯茜
Your dad's not here, Cassie...
这倒也不算太意外
but I guess that's not a big surprise.
康！
Kang!
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
你敢抓走我女儿！
You took my daughter!
活见鬼了
Holy shit.
真够大的
That's big.
你竟敢骗我！
You lied to me!
做人要讲信用
Our word is our bond.
不讲信用就不配做人！
Without that, we're nothing!
干掉他
Bring him down.
遵命
Yes, sir.
继续前进 杂兵交给我
Keep going. I've got them.
放马过来！
Yeah, come on!
敌人数量太多了！
There's so many!
斯科特！我挡不住了！
Scott! I can't hold them!
他们来了
They came.
干得好 凯茜！
Way to go, Cassie!
太好了！
Yes!
大家冲啊！
Come on! Let's go!
反攻！
Revolution!
把他们都干掉
Burn it all down.
上啊！
Fight!
躲好！趴下！
Cover! Get down!
大桥密码是多少？
What is the bridge code?
问我的尸体去
I'll die first.
One-eight-one-four-seven.
见鬼！
Damn!
你需要这个
You'll need this.
嗨
Hi.
这儿是我们的家园！
This is our home!
一起把它夺回来！
Let's take it back!
不！
No!
我有洞洞了
I have holes.
我有洞洞了！
I have holes!
我都不知道他还能这样
I didn't know he could do that.
康！
Kang!
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
立刻启动！
Launch now!
那是什么？
What is that?
他要跑了
He's getting out.
不 他休想
Oh, no, he's not.
别让他靠近圆环
Keep him away from the rings.
爸爸！
Dad!
爸爸 我来了！
Dad, I'm coming!
爸爸！
Dad!
看你再往哪儿逃
Nowhere left to run.
拜托一定要成功
Please let this work.
喂 你上哪儿去？
Hey, where do you think you're going?
跟我打
Let's go.
你以为这就完了？回来！接着打
You think this is over? Come on! Let's go.
达伦 够了
Darren, just stop...
别再做出这种鬼样子了
trying to be whatever this is.
我不知道该变成什么样
I don't know what to be.
你来告诉我
Tell me what to be.
不知道 反正别一副混蛋样
I don't know. Just don't be a dick.
已经晚了
It's too late.
你看我
Look at me.
已经成大混蛋了
I'm such a dick.
重新做人什么时候都不晚
It's never too late to stop being a dick.
我们必须拦下他
We've gotta stop him.
我想到个办法
I have an idea.
准备好了？
Ready?
恐怕还没
Probably not.
一二三 走！
One, two, three. Now!
爸爸！
Dad!
凯茜？
Cassie?
你变得好大！
You're huge.
我变得好大
I'm huge.
我爱你 小花生
I love you, Peanut.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
感觉像在跟哥斯拉抱抱
I feel like I'm hugging Godzilla.
是啊 实在太酷了
I know. It feels so cool.
我懂 对吧？
I know, right?
我肚子好饿
I'm so hungry.
会的 正常现象
Yeah, that happens.
-我什么都吃得下 -什么都吃得下
-I could eat everything. -Everything. I know.
-但我最想吃青柠 -是吧？
-But I really want like a lime. -Right?
-就想吃柑橘类 很奇怪 我懂 -柑橘类
-Citrus. It's weird. I know. -Citrus.
这…
It's...
攻下主塔！
Take the tower!
都结束了
It's over.
你还是不明白
You still can't see it.
永远都不会结束
It's never over.
-我们得快离开 -不行
-We have to go, right now. -No.
-快点 -不！
-Come on. -No!
我明白 但必须得走了
I know, I know, but we have to go.
-不！ -快走
-No! -Come on.
你这个混…
You son of a...
-天啊 -斯科特
-Oh, God. -Scott.
起来
Come on.
你们以为我第一次见这种事？
You think this is new to me?
你们知不知道我镇压过多少次叛乱？
Do you know how many rebellions I have put down?
不
No, no, no.
征服过多少个世界？
How many worlds I've conquered?
干掉过多少个复仇者？
How many Avengers I've killed?
就凭你们也妄想打败我？
And you think you can beat me?
我可是康！
I am Kang!
你们
You...
只配与蚂蚁为伍
You talk to ants.
我的名字叫达伦
My name is Darren...
我不是混蛋！
and I am not a dick!
抱歉 我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
蚂蚁太多了
Lotta ants.
这是你弄的？
Oh, is this you?
你点醒了我 凯茜
You were right about me, Cassie.
达伦
Darren.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
不太好
Probably not.
-达伦？ -嗨 霍普
-Darren? -Hi, Hope.
你剪头发了
You changed your hair.
这到底是怎么回事？
What the hell happened?
就是…
Yeah. No...
说来话长 回头告诉你
It's a whole thing. I'll tell you later.
你刚才…
That was...
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
谢谢 斯科特
Thanks, Scott.
你一直就像是我的亲兄弟
You always were a brother to me.
是吗？
I was?
当然了
I was.
至少我是作为…
And at least I died...
复仇者死去的
an Avenger.
对
Yeah.
-没错 -对
-You did. -Yeah.
你入伙了
You're in.
这一天发生了太多事
A lot has happened today.
-亨利？ -珍妮？
-Henry? -Janet?
-妈妈 你在哪儿？ -我在主塔
-Mom, where are you? -I'm in the tower.
我好像找到回去的机会了
I think I can give us one shot back.
不过得抓紧时间
But we don't have much time.
要想回去…
If we wanna go home...
现在就得走
we have to go now.
我们会收场的
We'll finish this.
谢谢
Thank you.
快点！该走了！
Come on! Let's go!
好的 祝你们好运
All right. Good luck.
保重 我们走
Good luck. Come on.
谢了 老弟
Thanks, buddy.
你成功了
You did it.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
斯科特人呢？
Where's Scott?
他刚才就在我后面
He was right behind me.
你真不该多管闲事
You should've looked the other way.
我就是管不住自己
Yeah, well, never been great at that.
你休想离开这儿
And you're not getting out.
我要你记住
I want you to remember.
你本来是能回去的
You could've gone home.
你本来能跟你女儿团聚
You could've seen your daughter again.
可你太相信自己能赢
But you thought you could win.
我不需要赢
I don't have to win.
只要你跟我一起输就行
We both just have to lose.
爸爸！
Dad!
在哪儿…
Where... Where...
她在哪儿？她…
Where is she? Is she...
-她没事 -她在哪儿？
-No, she's okay. -Where is she?
她没事
She's okay. She's okay.
-斯科特 他们都没事 -她安全了？
-Scott, they're all okay. They're all okay. -She's safe?
你成功了
You did it.
你做到了
-对不起 -别
-Sorry. Sorry, sorry. -No, no, no.
别放手
No, don't let go. Don't let go.
Don't let go.
永远都别放开
Don't ever let go.
我陪着你
I got you.
你回来了
You came back.
我爱你 霍普
I love you, Hope.
我爱你 斯科特
I love you, Scott.
回家吧
Let's go home.
家是最棒的
Home's good.
我生活中有很多荒唐事
My life doesn't make sense.
有段时间我常常问自己
I used to ask myself a lot of questions about that.
"斯科特 你带着一家老小拯救了量子领域"
"Scott you just saved the Quantum Realm with your family...
"还喝了一个没有洞洞的家伙的汁"
"and drank a guy without holes.
"这种事怎么总发生在你身上？"
"Why does this kind of stuff keep happening to you?
"这太荒唐了"
"That doesn't make any sense."
话又说回来
But you know what?
谁规定生活必须合情合理？
Who said life has to make sense?
鲁宾！
Rubin!
你是那什么虫！
You are the bug!
我以前搞错了 你是另外那只虫
I was wrong. Yeah. You are the other bug.
你是虫子侠
You're the bug man.
一会儿变大 一会儿变小 就像一只大虫子！
You get big and get small like a big bug!
没错 我就是 要一杯咖啡 谢谢
You're right. That's me. Just a coffee, please.
12块
Twelve dollar.
12块！
Twelve!
我想过要不要给这段经历画上句号
I used to wonder if this chapter in my life was over...
但凯茜提醒了我:"需要帮助的人无处不在"
but as Cassie reminded me, "There's always someone you can help."
为你重拾了做蛋糕的手艺
Came out of cake making retirement for you.
(生日快乐 凯茜)
哇哦
Wow.
这是你自己做的？
You made this yourself?
-对！我现在很少做蛋糕了 -我知道
-Yeah! I don't usually make the cakes. -I know.
上次做还是1997年的事
This is the first one I've made since 1997.
你太有才了
You're a real artist.
这一路走来起起落落
It's been a pretty wild ride.
前一天才被芭斯罗缤开除
One day you're fired from Baskin-Robbins...
第二天就打赢了穿越时空的宇宙魔王
the next you're beating a time-traveling space king.
是打赢了吧？
We did beat him, right?
就是这么回事
I mean, yeah, that's what happened.
他想逃走但没逃成
He was getting out and he didn't get out.
应该吧
I think.
可他还说要是他没逃出去
But he also said something bad was coming...
那就会出大事 大家都会死
and that everyone would die if he didn't get out.
等等 这么说我把大家给害了？
Wait. So, did I just kill everyone?
因为我干的事大家都要死了？
Is everyone gonna die because of me?
天啊
Oh, my God.
天…我干了什么？
Oh my... What did I do?
我干了什么？
What did I do?
算了 应该没什么事
You know what? It's probably fine.
生活中荒唐的事多了去了
Like I said, life doesn't make any sense...
何必问这问那纠结这么多呢 斯科特
so maybe stop asking so many questions, Scott.
别想太多了
Stop overthinking it.
惊喜！
Surprise!
祝你生日快乐
Happy Birthday to you
今天不是我生日
It's not my birthday.
我知道 前几年你生日我不在
I know. But I missed a few.
这样就好 平安团圆
This is good. We're all together.
没事的
You're fine.
应该不会发生什么事
Everything's probably fine.
康不在了 你赢了
Kang's gone. You did it.
把他的事抛到脑后去吧
Don't have to worry about that guy anymore.
谢谢
Thanks.
不是生日的生日快乐 凯茜
Happy fake birthday, Cassie.
《蚁人与黄蜂女：量子狂潮》
那个被流放的家伙死了
So, the exiled one is dead.
你确定他死了？
You sure he's dead?
要是假消息 我也不会叫你们来
If it wasn't true, I wouldn't call you.
他没死在你手里 你一定气坏了吧
Must really eat you up, that you're not the one who killed him.
我们谁都没能…
None of us...
把他杀死
killed him.
他们做到了
They did.
他们开始接触多元宇宙了
They're beginning to touch the Multiverse.
如果放任不管…
And if we let them...
他们会夺走…
they will take...
我们建立的…
everything...
所有成果
we've built.
都别再浪费时间了
So let's stop wasting time.
要晚了
We're late.
你叫来了多少？
How many did you call?
我们所有的人
All of us.
时间即是一切
Time is everything.
(维克托·坦姆利)
它塑造我们的一生
It shapes our lives.
或许我们也能重塑…
But, perhaps, we can shape...
时间
it.
就是他
It's him.
干嘛？你这语气搞得好像他是什么大魔王
What? You made him sound like this terrifying figure.
他就是
He is.
康将卷土重来